In this video, we will be visiting this
question
and looking at how to draw the free-body
diagram
for it. Everything else in this question,
we
will visit in a later video when we have
learned
about gravity, normal force, and friction.
But first of all, let's see.
The question first wants to draw a
free-body
diagram. And a free-body diagram is
basically
a diagram that shows and demonstrates all
the
forces acting on an object, in this case,
crate. So let's see the question. A five
kilogram
crate is placed on a rough horizontal
floor.
The crate is pulled to the right by a net
force
of 18 newtons. Sorry, not net, by a
horizontal
force of 18 newtons. The coefficient of
kinetic
friction between the crate and the floor
is,
we don't need to know that, we will learn
that
later. But first of all, let's draw all
the
forces acting on the crate. The first
thing
you want to think of when drawing all the
forces
is, in most questions, in 99% of the
questions,
unless it occurs in space, there will
always
be a gravity component.
And we would call that FG, or we can
sometimes
denote that as MG, depends on how you want
to
portray that. Next, what we have is
something
called the normal force. Why is there a
normal
force? Well, remember Newton's third law.
For every action, there's an equal and
opposite
reaction. So if the box is leaning on the
floor
and it exerts a force of FG on the floor
because
of its weight, then there will be an equal
and
opposite reaction that the floor exerts
back
on that box. And we will call that F
normal.
Without this normal force, the box will
just
slide down through the box.
Next, we have it being pulled to the right
by
a horizontal force of 18 Newton's. I
forgot
to mention that most of the times forces
are
denoted from the center when we're talking
about
things like external forces, for example,
in
this case, or gravity. So over here we
have
a force. Let's call this force applied.
You can denote this whatever you want, but
usually
it would be applied force. And this is 18
Newton's.
And now we need another force because it's
a
rough horizontal floor.
So there will be a friction force. I'll
denote
this friction force coming from here
because
it's between the floor and the box.
You can also do it here.
Really doesn't matter, but putting it here
would
make it more accurate and make it easier
to
visualize. And we could call this F of
friction.
And that is basically free body diagrams.
How about let's have another example down
here.
Let's say we have a ball. Let's say this
would
be the diagram that's not free body, just
a
normal diagram. Now, let's say this is a
pendulum
and the ball starts from here and it's
going
to go swing back and forth. Now, what are
the
forces acting on this ball? Let's draw it
out
in a free-body diagram here.
First of all, as always, there's gravity.
And to counteract that gravity, there's
also
going to be a tension force that partially
counteracts
that. So we would call that F t and F g.
There will also be air resistance, but in
most
problems at this level, we won't need to
take
into account. The problem will probably
say
air resistance is neglected, so we can
ignore
that. Sometimes it's going to give you the
angle
at which the pendulum is released. We'll
get
into that in another unit. But that angle
is
the same as the angle on a free-body
diagram,
which makes a free-body diagram really,
really
useful for calculating these things.
And that's it for an introduction of free
body
diagrams. Remember, there will always be
gravity.
There will usually be a normal force,
especially
if it's on a surface and you do applied
forces
starting from the middle.
Thank you guys for watching.